Guide to the H.D. Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1905-1961; Series I; 7.5; (19 boxes)
  - INCOMING
    - Duncan, Robert Edward, 1949-61 (Box 9, Folder 319-20)
    - Durand, Lionel, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 321)
    - Dutton, Geoffrey, Mr. and Mrs., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 322)
    - "E" general, 1951, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 323)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1960-61 (Box 9, Folder 324)
    - Eissler, Kurt, 1954
    - Eliot, T. S., 1943 (Box 9, Folder 325)
    - Ellerman, Hannah Glover, 1935-39 (Box 9, Folder 326)
    - Ellerman, John Reeves, [192?]-27 (Box 10, Folder 327)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1922-38 (Box 10, Folder 328)
    - "F" general, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 329)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 330)
    - Frere, Philip, 1942-57 (Box 10, Folder 331)
    - Freud, Anna, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 332)
    - Freud, Martha, 1938-45 (Box 10, Folder 333)
    - Freud, Sigmund, 1932-38 (Box 10, Folder 334-35)
    - Freud, Sigmund [photocopies], 1932-38 (Box 10, Folder 336-37)
    - Freud, Sigmund [transcripts and, 1927-38 (Box 10, Folder 338)
    - translations ]
    - Freud, Sigmund [transcripts and, 1927-38 (Box 10, Folder 339)
    - translations: H.D.]
    - Freud, Sigmund [transcripts and, 1932-38 (Box 10, Folder 340-41)
    - translations: Pearson photocopies]
    - Friend's Central School, 1956-60 (Box 10, Folder 342)
    - "G" general, 1956-60 (Box 10, Folder 343)
    - Gallup, Donald, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 344)
    - Gellhorn, Martha, [193?]
    - Gibson, Andrew, 1952
    - Gray, Cecil, 1918 (Box 10, Folder 345)
    - Great Britain Admiralty, 1932-44 (Box 10, Folder 346)
    - Gregory, Horace and Marya Zaturenska, 1944-61 (Box 10, Folder 347)
    - Gregory, Patrick, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 348)
    - Gunther, Alfred, 1956-61
    - "H" general, 1934-59 (Box 10, Folder 349)
    - Hart, Ellen, 1945-61 (Box 10, Folder 350)
    - Henderson, Gerald, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 351)
    - Herf, Bertha, 1955-56
    - Herr, Mary E., 1959 (Box 10, Folder 352)
    - Herring, Robert, 1928-48 (Box 10, Folder 353-64)
    - Herring, Robert, 1949-61, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 365-70)
    - Hesse, Hermann, 1947-57 (Box 11, Folder 371)
    - Hesse, Marulla, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 372)
    - Hesse, Ninon, 1947-50
    - Heydt, Erich, 1954-61, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 373-75)
    - Hicks, Margery, 1959-61 (Box 11, Folder 376)
    - Hipskund, Guin Doolittle, [195?]
    - Horner, David, 1943-45 (Box 11, Folder 377)
    - Horner, Isaline Blew, 1959-60
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1924-43 (Box 11, Folder 378)
    - Howard, Agnes Seidel, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 379)
    - Howard, Clifford, 1927-42 (Box 11, Folder 380-81)
    - Howard, Hattie, 1942-50 (Box 11, Folder 382)
    - Howard, Hildegarde, 1942-60 (Box 11, Folder 383)
    - Hughes, Molly, 1941-47 (Box 11, Folder 384-86)
    - Hughes, Randolph, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 387)
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 388)
    - "J" general, 1947, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 389)
    - Jenkins, Laura Wolle, 1927-32 (Box 11, Folder 390)
    - Jordan, Barbara, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 391)
    - Jordan, Viola, 1949-61, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 392-94)
    - "K" general, 1951-52 (Box 11, Folder 395)
    - Kash, Christine, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 396)
    - Katibah, Helen Doolittle, 1956-57
    - Keeney, Sue Dorothy, 1958
    - "L" general, 1933-56 (Box 11, Folder 397)
    - La Marche-Sacriste, Louis, 1944-45 (Box 11, Folder 398)
    - Latimer, Ronald Lane, 1934-36 (Box 11, Folder 399)
    - Laughlin, James, 1948
    - Lawrence, D. H., 1929 (Box 11, Folder 400)
    - Leader, Ethel, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 401)
    - Leslie, Doris, 1944
    - Levertov, Denise, 1960-61 (Box 11, Folder 402)
    - Lewin, Blanche, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 403)
    - Lewison, Ludwig, 1932
    - Little, Neil, 1934
    - London Library, 1942
    - Long, Doris, 1956-61 (Box 11, Folder 404)
    - Longmans, Green, and Company, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 405)
    - Lowenfels, Walter, 1929
    - Ludeke, Henry, 1958
    - Lyons, Islay, 1951-61 (Box 12, Folder 406-07)
    - "M" general, 1932-60 (Box 12, Folder 408)
    - McAlmon, Robert, 1928-52 (Box 12, Folder 409-11)
    - Mackenzie, Faith Compton, 1943-51 (Box 12, Folder 412)
    - Macmillan and Company, 1948-50 (Box 12, Folder 413)
    - Macpherson, Eileen, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 414)
    - Macpherson, John, 1950
    - Macpherson, Kenneth, 1927-61, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 415-28)
    - Martinelli, Sheri, 1956-61 (Box 12, Folder 429-31)
    - Mase, Georgina, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 432)
    - Masefield, John, 1947-52 (Box 12, Folder 433)
    - Mayne, Ethel Colburn, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 434)
    - Monnier, Adrienne, 1953
    - Moore, Marianne, 1921-60 (Box 12, Folder 435-37)
    - Moore, Mary Warner, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 438)
    - Moore, Merrill, 1938-57
    - Murray, D. L., 1945
    - "N" general, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 439)
    - Nagy, Niclas Christoph de, 1960-61 (Box 12, Folder 440)
    - Norman, Charles, 1959-60 (Box 12, Folder 441)
    - "O" general, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 442)
    - Oxford University Press, 1944-46 (Box 13, Folder 443)
    - "P" general, 1943-60 (Box 13, Folder 444)
    - Parkham, Nellie E., 1927-44 (Box 13, Folder 445)
    - Patmore, Brigit, 1922-30 (Box 13, Folder 446-50)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1938-61, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 451-71)
    - Pearson, Susan, 1950-61 (Box 13, Folder 472)
    - Peiter, Annie Jenkins, 1927 (Box 13, Folder 473)
    - Plank, George, 1927-48 (Box 13, Folder 474)
    - Plank, George, 1949-61, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 475-82)
    - Pound, Dorothy, 1949-61 (Box 14, Folder 483)
    - Pound, Ezra, 1922-61 (Box 14, Folder 484-89)
    - Pratt, Margaret Snively, 1927-60 (Box 14, Folder 490-91)
    - Pulsifer, Susan, 1950-51 (Box 14, Folder 492)
    - "R" general, 1959-60 (Box 14, Folder 493)
    - Rachewiltz, Mary de, 1952-61 (Box 14, Folder 494)
    - Richardson, Dorothy, 1923-50 (Box 14, Folder 495)
    - Rogers, William D., 1959 (Box 14, Folder 496)
    - Rudge, Olga, 1946-53 (Box 14, Folder 497)
    - Russell, Alys, 1946-49 (Box 14, Folder 498)
    - Russell, Peter, 1950-53
    - "S" general, 1934-60 (Box 14, Folder 499)
    - Sackville-West, Vita, 1944-45 (Box 14, Folder 500)
    - Sarton, May, 1944-49 (Box 14, Folder 501)
    - Scarlett, Marie, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 502)
    - Scarlett, Olive, n.d.
    - Schaffner, John, 1950-60 (Box 14, Folder 503-04)
    - Schaffner, Perdita, 1923-61, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 505-26)
    - Schmideberg, Melitta, 1950-60 (Box 15, Folder 527)
    - Schmideberg, Walter, 1935-54 (Box 16, Folder 528-31)
    - Schnack, Elizabeth, 1954-61 (Box 16, Folder 532)
    - Schur, Max, 1957-61 (Box 16, Folder 533)
    - Serbanne, Claude, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 534)
    - Shakespear, Olivia, [192?]
    - Sinclair, May, 1925-26 (Box 16, Folder 535)
    - Singleton, Elizabeth, 1961
    - Sitwell, Edith, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 536-38)
    - Sitwell, Osbert, 1939-[195?] (Box 16, Folder 539)
    - Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 540)
    - Smith, Logan Pearsall, 1941-45
    - Society of Authors, 1925-45 (Box 16, Folder 541)
    - Street, Florence Prince, 1949-59 (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - Suhrkamp Verlag, 1955-56 (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - Sutcliffe, Rosemary, 1957-60 (Box 16, Folder 544)
    - Swann, Thomas Burnett, 1959-60 (Box 16, Folder 545)
    - "T" general, 1956-60 (Box 16, Folder 546)
    - Theodore Goddard and Company, 1937-39 (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - Trumper, Jeanette K., 1942-61 (Box 16, Folder 548)
    - "U" general, 1945, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 549)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1953-60 (Box 16, Folder 550)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1924
    - Urzidil, Johannes, 1955-60 (Box 16, Folder 551)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 552)
    - Volkert, Elsie, 1952-61 (Box 16, Folder 553)
    - "W" general, 1937-52 (Box 16, Folder 554)
    - Waluga, Joan Leader, [195?] (Box 16, Folder 555)
    - Weaver, Harriet Shaw, 1928-32
    - Wellesley, Dorothy, 1943
    - White, Eric Walter, 1934-61 (Box 16, Folder 556-57)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 558)
    - Williamson, Lydia Hunn, 1930-61
    - Wolff, Kurt, 1954
    - Wolle, Francis, 1929-60 (Box 16, Folder 559)
    - Wulfing, Sulamith, 1948-54 (Box 16, Folder 560)
    - Wunderling, Carrie, Martha Wunderling, Ruth Young, and Michael Yudkin, 1927-1952 (Box 16, Folder 561)
    - Zaturenska, Marya
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: Box 10, folder 347
    - Letter fragments, 1942, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 562)
    - Folder numbers 563-565 are not used.
  - OUTGOING
    - Aldington, Richard, 1953-61, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 566-71)
    - Baker, Gretchen Wolle, 1934-56, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 572-76)
    - Beach, Sylvia, [194?]-60, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 577)
    - Blackwell, Basil, Sir, 1928 (Box 17, Folder 578)
    - Brooks, J. Elliot, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 579)
    - Capper, Jessie, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 580)
    - Caroll, Dennis, 1946
    - Cole, M. D., 1951
    - Cournos, John [transcripts], 1916-28 (Box 17, Folder 581-82)
    - Cournos, John [photocopies of letters], 1916-19 (Box 17, Folder 583)
    - Doolittle, Helen Wolle, 1911-18 (Box 17, Folder 584)
    - Dowding, Sir Hugh, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 585)
    - Duncan, Robert, 1959-61 (Box 17, Folder 586-87)
    - Durand, Lionel, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 588)
    - Ellerman, Hannah Glover, 1919-33
    - Flint, F. S., 1912-20 (Box 17, Folder 589-90)
    - Foster, C. H., 1946 (Box 17, Folder 591)
    - Henderson, Cole, 1951
    - Herr, Mary E., 1940-58 (Box 17, Folder 592-93)
    - Herring, Robert, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 594)
    - Hesse, Hermann and Ninon, [1950?] (Box 17, Folder 595)
    - Howard, Clifford, 1938-48 (Box 17, Folder 596)
    - Howard, Hattie, 1941-45 (Box 17, Folder 597)
    - Landis, Isabel Potts, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 598)
    - Long, Doris, [194?]-45 (Box 17, Folder 599)
    - McBride, Katharine, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 600)
    - McDougal, John, 1936
    - Macpherson, Kenneth, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 601)
    - Nagy, Niclas Christoph de, 1960-61 (Box 17, Folder 602)
    - Pitt, Hewitt, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 603)
    - Plank, George, 1955
    - Richardson, Richard, [1951?]
    - Russell, Peter, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 604)
    - Schaffner, Perdita, [192?]-49] (Box 18, Folder 605)
    - Schmideberg, Walter, 1946-54 (Box 18, Folder 606)
    - Skidmore, Sidney, Mrs., 1905-08 (Box 18, Folder 607)
    - Die Tat, 1960
    - Urzidil, Johannes, 1955
    - Volkert, Elsie, 1951-60 (Box 18, Folder 608)
    - White, Eric Walter, 1931-56 (Box 18, Folder 609-10)
    - Wilkinson, Frances Gregg, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 611)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Aldington, Richard: A-Z, 1924-61 (Box 19, Folder 612)
    - Bryher: A-Z, 1924-61 (Box 19, Folder 613)
    - Bryher: unidentified, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 614)
    - Doolittle, Helen Wolle to:
      - Perdita Schaffner, [192?] (Box 19, Folder 615)
      - Mrs. Sidney Skidmore, 1905-08
    - Doolittle, Sara to:, 1905-08
      - J. Fred Wolle, n.y. May 23 (Box 19, Folder 616)
    - Ellerman, Hannah Glover to:, n.y. May 23
      - Perdita Schaffner, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 617)
    - Farrelly, John A. to:, 1925
      - Sara Doolittle, 1918 (Box 19, Folder 618)
    - Grahame, Lewis to:, 1918
      - Richard Aldington, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 619)
    - Howard, Clifford to:, 1953
      - Perdita Schaffner, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 620)
    - McAlmon, Robert: A-Z, 1925-26 (Box 19, Folder 621)
    - Pound, Ezra to:
      - Margaret Snively Pratt, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 622)
    - Pratt, Margaret Snively to:, 1955
      - Mrs. Sidney Skidmore, [1905?] (Box 19, Folder 623)
      - Helen Wolle Doolittle, 1925
- Writings, 1918-77; Series II; 11; (27 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, contains 27 boxes of writings. The material consists of Novels, Poetry, Short Stories, Autobiographical Writings, and Miscellaneous Writings. The arrangement is alphabetical by title within each subseries. Two boxes of Writings of Others are placed at the end of the series and are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - NOVELS
    - Asphodel
      - Part I, typescript, 1921-22 (Box 20, Folder 624-26)
      - Part II, typescript, 1921-22 (Box 20, Folder 627-29)
    - Bid Me to Live
      - Parts I-IX, typescript, first draft, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 630-32)
      - Parts I-XI, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D. (Box 20, Folder 633-38)
      - Galley proofs, corrected by H.D., 1959 (Box 20, Folder 639)
      - Proofs, uncorrected.
        See: Related Papers, Box 63, folder 1432
      - Reviews, 1960 (Box 20, Folder 640)
    - Hedylus
      - Parts I-XXII, typescript, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 641-42)
      - Parts I-XXII, typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 643-44)
      - Additional corrections, ca. 1951 (Box 21, Folder 645)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 646-47)
      - Page proofs, corrected, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 648-49)
      - Verse selections, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 650)
      - Reviews, 1929-34 (Box 21, Folder 651)
    - Her
      - Pages 1-317, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1927 (Box 21, Folder 652-55)
      - Pages 1-317, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., photocopy, 1927 (Box 22, Folder 656-59)
      - Pages 1-282, typescript, second draft (Box 22, Folder 660-63)
    - Magic Mirror
      - Parts I-VIII, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1956, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 664-65)
      - Parts I-VII, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D. (Box 22, Folder 666-67)
      - Part VIII, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D. (Box 23, Folder 668)
      - Parts I-VIII, typescript, second draft, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1956, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 669-70)
    - Majic Ring
      - Pages 1-247, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1943-44 (Box 23, Folder 671-73)
      - Pages 1-310, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D. (Box 23, Folder 674-77)
      - Pages 1-310, typescript, second draft, carbon, corrected by H.D., 1943-44 (Box 23, Folder 678-81)
      - Source material, 1924-45 (Box 23, Folder 682)
    - The Mystery
      - Chapters 1-19, 4 notebooks, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 683-84)
      - Parts 1-2, typescript, first draft, 1948 (Box 24, Folder 685-86)
      - Chapters 1-14, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D. (Box 24, Folder 687-88)
      - Chapters 1-19, typescript, second draft, carbon, corrected by H.D. (Box 24, Folder 689-90)
      - Third draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 691)
      - Third draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 692)
      - Chapters 1-19, typescript, third draft, photocopy, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 693-94)
      - Chapters 3, 14-19, typescript, third draft, photocopy, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 695)
      - Zinzendorf notes, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 696)
    - Paint it Today
      - Chapters I-VIII, typescript, carbon, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1921 (Box 24, Folder 697-98)
      - Chapters I-VIII, typescript, second draft, carbon, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 699-700)
    - Pilate's Wife
      - Chapters I-XI, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1924-34 (Box 24, Folder 701-02)
      - Chapters I-XI, typescript, second draft (Box 25, Folder 703-04)
      - Chapters I-XI, typescript, second draft, carbon, corrected by H.D., ca. 1954 (Box 25, Folder 705-06)
    - The Sword Went Out to Sea
      - Book II, sections I-V, typescript, first draft, [Book I missing], n.d. (Box 25, Folder 707-10)
      - Book I, Part I, [sections] I-III, typescript, second draft (Box 25, Folder 711-13)
      - Book I, Part II, [sections] I-VI, typescript, second draft, 1947, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 714-15)
      - Book II, [sections] I-VI, typescript, second draft (Box 25, Folder 716-17)
      - Book II, [sections] VII-XIX, typescript, second draft, 1947, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 718-19)
      - Book I, Part I, [sections] I-III, typescript, second draft, carbon, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 720-22)
      - Book I, Part II, [sections] I-VI, typescript, second draft, carbon, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 723-24)
      - Book II, [sections] I-XIV, typescript, second draft, carbon, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 725-28)
      - Book I, Part I, [sections] I-III, typescript, third draft, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 729-31)
      - Book I, Part II, [sections] I-VI, typescript, third draft, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 732-33)
      - Book II, [sections] I-III, typescript, third draft, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 734)
      - Book II, [sections] IV-XIV, typescript, third draft, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 735-37)
    - Tattler
      - [From a novel], typescript, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 738)
    - The White Rose and the Red
      - Pages 2-540, Parts I-VI, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1948 (Box 27, Folder 739-44)
      - Part VIII, typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 27, Folder 745)
      - Pages 2-282, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D., 1948 (Box 27, Folder 746-48)
      - Pages 283-565, typescript, second draft, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 749-51)
      - Pages 2-568, typescript, third draft, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 752-57)
      - Pages 2-300, typescript, fourth draft, 1948 (Box 28, Folder 758-60)
      - Pages 301-598, typescript, fourth draft, 1948 (Box 29, Folder 761-63)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 764)
  - POETRY
    - A-Z (Box 30, Folder 765)
    - "Ancient Wisdom Speaks," typescript, first-fourth draft, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 766-69)
    - "Archer," typescript, two drafts, ca. 1952 (Box 30, Folder 770)
    - "Ariadene," typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 771)
    - "Body and Soul," typescript and galley proof (Box 30, Folder 772)
    - By Avon River
      - Part I, typescript, first draft, ca. 1945 (Box 30, Folder 773-74)
      - Part I, typescript, second draft, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 775-77)
      - Part I, galley proofs, corrected by H.D., 1945 (Box 30, Folder 778)
      - Part II, holograph, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 779)
      - Part II, typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., ca. 1946 (Box 30, Folder 780)
      - Part II, typescript, second draft, corrected by H.D., ca. 1946 (Box 30, Folder 781-82)
      - Part II, editor's questions on text, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 783)
      - German translation by Johannes Urzidil, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 784)
      - German translation-variant version, 1950 (Box 30, Folder 785)
      - Reviews, 1959 (Box 30, Folder 786)
    - "Child Poems"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 787)
    - Collected Poems
      - Reviews, 1925 (Box 30, Folder 788)
    - "The Dancer"
      - Typescript, corrected by H.D., n.d. (Box 30, Folder 789)
    - A Dead Priestess Speaks
      - "A Dead Priestess Speaks," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 30, Folder 790-92)
      - "Electra-Orestes," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D (Box 30, Folder 793-96)
      - "Callypso," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 30, Folder 797-99)
      - "In our Town," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 30, Folder 800-01)
      - "Delphi," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 31, Folder 802-03)
      - "Dodona," typescript, with carbon, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 804)
      - "Sigil VIII-XIX," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D., 1931 (Box 31, Folder 805-06)
      - "Sigil" selection, typescript, ca. 1952 (Box 31, Folder 807)
      - "Priest," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 31, Folder 808-809)
      - "Master [Magician]," typescript, first and second drafts, corrected by H.D. (Box 31, Folder 810-11)
    - "Erige Corteum ad mein Caelium"
      - Typescript, ca. 1950 (Box 31, Folder 812)
    - Euripides Ion
      - Page proofs, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 813-14)
      - Selections, holograph, ca. 1937 (Box 31, Folder 815)
      - Selections, typescript, ca. 1937 (Box 31, Folder 816)
      - Reviews, 1937, 1954 (Box 31, Folder 817)
    - The Flowering of the Rod
      - Notebook, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 818)
      - Typescript, first draft, corrected by H.D., 1944 (Box 31, Folder 819)
      - Deleted sections, first draft, 1944 (Box 31, Folder 820)
      - Typescript, second draft, corrected, 1945 (Box 31, Folder 821)
      - Deleted sections, second draft (Box 31, Folder 822)
      - Galley proofs, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 823)
      - German translation by Elizabeth Schnack, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 824)
      - Reviews, 1947 (Box 31, Folder 825)
    - "Georgius Sanctus"
      - Typescript, third draft, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 826)
    - Helen in Egypt
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 827)
      - "Pallinode," notebook, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 828)
      - "Leuke," notebook, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 829)
      - "Eidolon," notebook, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 830)
      - "Captions," notebook, 1924 (Box 31, Folder 831)
      - "Pallinode" [selections], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 832)
      - "Leuke" [selections], n.d. (Box 31, Folder 833)
      - First draft, typescript, corrected by H.D.
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 834-35)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 836)
        - "Eidolon", n.d. (Box 31, Folder 837)
        - ["Captions"], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 838)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D.
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 839)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 840)
        - "Eidolon", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 841)
      - Second draft, typescript, corrected by H.D.
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 842)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 843)
        - "Eidolon", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 844)
      - Third draft, typescript, corrected by H.D.
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 845)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 846)
        - "Eidolon", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 847)
        - ["Captions"], n.d. (Box 32, Folder 848)
        - Corrections, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 849)
      - Third draft, typescript, corrected by H.D.
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 850)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 851)
        - "Eidolon", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 852)
        - "Captions", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 853)
      - Third draft, typescript, corrected by H.D., [Some leaves removed and used in making the recording of Helen in Egypt .]
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 854)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 855)
        - "Eidolon", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 856)
        - Leaves removed from previous folders, 1955 (Box 32, Folder 857)
      - Third draft, typescript, selections
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 858)
        - "Leuke", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 859)
      - Fourth draft, typescript, corrected by Norman Holmes Pearson
        - "Pallinode", n.d. (Box 32, Folder 860-61)
        - Selections, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 862)
      - Fifth draft, typescript, used as setting typescript
        - "Pallinode", 1961 (Box 32, Folder 863)
        - "Leuke", 1961 (Box 33, Folder 864)
        - "Eidolon", 1961 (Box 33, Folder 865)
      - Fifth draft, typescript, carbon, corrected by H.D.
        - "Pallinode" [2 copies], n.d. (Box 33, Folder 866-67)
        - "Leuke" [2 copies], n.d. (Box 33, Folder 868-69)
        - "Eidolon" [2 copies], n.d. (Box 33, Folder 870-71)
      - "Pallinode"
        - [Selections], unidentified drafts, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 872)
      - Galley proofs, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 873)
      - Page proofs, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 874-75)
      - Reviews, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 876)
      - Tapes, reels 1-3, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 877-79)
        Digital reference copy is available
    - Heliodora and Other Poems
      - Selections, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 880)
      - Reviews, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 881)
    - "Helios and Athene"
      - Typescript, 1920 (Box 33, Folder 882)
    - Hermetic Definition
      - Notebooks, 1960 (Box 34, Folder 883)
      - "Sagesse," notebooks, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 884)
      - "Winterlove," first draft, notebook, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 885)
      - "Winterlove," second draft, notebook, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 886)
      - First draft, corrected by H.D.
        - Typescript, 1961 (Box 34, Folder 887)
        - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 888)